[GinTama the anime is entering its final chapter!]
["Entering the Final Chapter!"]
[Odd Jobs Gin]
(新八)いや… ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』も
ついに 最終章 突入ですね！
Well, it looks like the GinTama anime
is finally entering its final chapter.
(銀時)まさかなぁ
３年目の折り返しで➡
I never expected this to happen
in the middle of the third year.
こんなことになるとはなぁ｡
(神楽)最近のｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟｱﾆﾒは➡
Lately, JUMP anime just drag on
and on, and when they end,
みんな引っ張るだけ引っ張って
終わるときは 突然➡
it's like "Our battle has only just begun."
[Note: Refers to D. Grayman,
which ended like that.]
｢ｵﾚたちの戦いは これからだ｣
ｴﾝﾄﾞね｡
こないだ終わった
｢…Gray-man｣ もそうだったある｡
D. [bleep]man was just like that.
まぁ ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』の終了は残念だが
これから最後まで➡
Well, It's unfortunate that the
GinTama anime is ending,
but let's do our best until the very end!
力一杯 やろうぜ！
All right!
(３人)おぉ！
それで いつまでなの？
So how long do we have?
え…｡
(神楽)最終章って何回ｱﾙか？
Huh?
How many episodes is the final chapter?
When is the final episode?
いつ最終回ｱﾙか？
あぁ それは…｡
Oh, well...
What? It hasn't been decided yet?
なに 決まってないの？
(神楽)え～ どういうことｱﾙか？
What? What's the big idea?
Well, how should I put this? Umm...
まぁ なんていうか…
その… 最終回は➡
the final episode is...in about
half a year from now.
半年後くらいかな…｡
(神楽)なんだと～!?
What?!
We're half a year from the final episode?!
How long is this final chapter?!
最終回の半年前からって
どんだけ長い最終章!?
ちょっとした深夜ｱﾆﾒなら
２ｼｰｽﾞﾝ分だよ！
That's enough for about two seasons
of a late night anime!
[Note: Three months is the usual length
for one season of late night anime.]
(神楽)あれｱﾙか
最近 ﾄﾞﾗﾏとかでよくやる➡
Is it that the type of thing they've
been pulling in TV dramas lately-
｢終わる終わる詐欺｣ｱﾙか？
that scam, where they keep saying
they're going to end?
When you look at the TV schedule, you
think it's going to be the final episode.
ﾃﾚﾋﾞ欄で最終回かと思ってみると
まだ全然 最終回じゃなくて➡
But when you watch it, it's
not the final episode at all.
最終章前編とか最終章第二部とか
最終章完結編とか➡
It's the first half of the last chapter,
or the second part of the final chapter,
or the conclusion of the final chapter.
いつまでも
ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗ ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗ引っ張る あれｱﾙか？
Is it that ploy where it keeps
dragging on and on?
まぁ その…
そのとおりなんだけど…➡
Well, umm, that's right...
いや なんかね
ｱﾆﾒ３年目も中だるみ気味なんで➡
The third year of this anime
is getting kind of dull,
so I thought we should
get a little enthusiastic.
このへんで ちょっと
盛り上げようかなとか思って…｡
Aww... I don't feel like doing
anything anymore.
あぁ～ もう やる気なくなった｡
You said it was the final chapter,
so I was getting excited.
(神楽)せっかく最終章だって
言うから気合い入れて来たのに｡
ちょっと二人とも…｡
今日は もうやめにしよう｡
Hey, you two...
Let's end for today.
(神楽)そうｱﾙな！
えっ！ そんな!!
Yeah.
What? No way!
というわけで 今日の 『銀魂』は➡
Anyway, GinTama is over for today.
これで終わりです｡
(神楽)また来週ｱﾙ！
See you next week, uh-huh.
[Preview]
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-What
should I do?
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-What should
I write in a l-l-letter?!
What are you getting all flustered
about, Shinpachi?
Just leave this to me!
The next episode... "Some Things Can Only
Be Conveyed Through the Written Word."
(銀時)は～い
次はｷﾝｸﾞｺﾝｸﾞのお二人 よろしく！
Next is the King Kong twosome. Thanks.
[NOTE: King Kong is a Japanese
standup comedy team.]
H-Hey!
ちょ ちょっと！ まだ始まって
６分半しかたってないんですけど｡
It's only been six and a half
minutes since we started!
Shut up. We've already done the
ending credits and the preview.
うるせえな
もう ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞも次回予告も➡
やっちゃったんだから
終わりでいいだろう｡
We can call it a day, can't we?
If we end here, it'll be dead air!
こんなところで終わっちゃったら
放送事故なんですけど！
No, we've shown only this background since
we started. It's already like dead air.
いや 始まってから
ずっと このBGｵﾝﾘｰな時点で➡
すでに事故みたいなもんだろ？
Still...
そんなこと言ったって…｡
ということで➡
Anyway, GinTama is over for today.
今日の 『銀魂』は
これで終わりです｡
Everyone, we won't do anything
even if you keep watching!
みんな もう見てても
何もやんないｱﾙよ！
は～い
次はｷﾝｸﾞｺﾝｸﾞのお二人 よろしく！
Next is the King Kong twosome. Thanks.
いやいや… まずいから
偉い人に怒られちゃうから！
No, no, no, no, no, no. This is bad.
Our superiors will be furious.
They're already mad at us
for a lot of other things.
もう すでに
いろいろ怒られてんだろ？
The producer has already written
several apologies this year.
ﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰ 今年に入って
何枚始末書 書いたよ？
Mu-san was moved to a different
department, too.
[Note: Mu-san is now the producer
of an Ad agency.]
ﾑｰさんなんか 別の部署に
飛ばされたｱﾙ｡
We can just write another apology.
もう一枚くらい
始末書 書きゃいいじゃん！
そういうわけには
いかないでしょう｡
We can't do that.
If I say it's over, it's over.
終わりと言ったら終わりなの｡
このあとは➡
After this, watch [bleep]
until Konkon Hills starts.
[Note: Bleep covers Nintama Rantaro, a ninja anime for
little kids. Kinkon Hills is a Japanese variety show.]
『ｷﾝｺﾝﾋﾙｽﾞ』 までの間
｢…｣ をご覧くださいｱﾙ｡
は～い
次はｷﾝｸﾞｺﾝｸﾞのお二人 よろしく！
Next is the King Kong twosome. Thanks.
I'm sorry! This is my fault!
悪かった！
ﾎﾞｸが悪うございました！
Let's do this properly.
Okay? Okay? Okay?
だから ちゃんとやりましょうよ
ねっ ねっ ねっ！
Oh well. Let's fill up the time.
しかたねえな！
じゃあ 時間まで埋めるか｡
Phew...
ふぅ… よかった｡
でも もうやる気ないｱﾙよ｡
Thank goodness.
But I don't feel like doing
anything anymore.
For times like this, we'll do that thing
with that thing like we always do.
そんなときは あれだよ お前
いつものあれで あれするんだよ｡
おぉ… あれを あれしとけば
ﾔﾂら全員 あれあるな｡
Oh. If we do that thing with that
thing, they'll all do that thing.
I-I feel a sense of déjà vu...
な なんだ この
ﾃﾞｼﾞｬﾋﾞｭ的な あれは…｡
Anyway, we're going to
a commercial break.
というわけで いったんCMです｡
We'll be dragging on like this even
after the commercial break.
CMの後も こんな感じで
ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗ続きます｡
Anyway, we could have ended the episode
with thirty minutes of only that background,
というわけで あのままBGｵﾝﾘｰで➡
30分終わらせても よかったんだが
そういうわけにもいかないと➡
but we were told we couldn't do that.
言われたんで
ここからは 寄せ集めの➡
So we're going to make due
with a mish-mash recap.
総集編で お茶を濁すことにする｡
じゃあ 新八
お前から ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』を振り返れ｡
All right, Shinpachi, you can start us off
by looking back on the GinTama anime.
まぁ 『銀魂』を語るうえで
欠かせないｴﾋﾟｿｰﾄﾞといえば➡
Well, if you're talking about GinTama, there's
one episode that you've got to mention.
あれしかないですね｡
Back then, I...
あのとき ﾎﾞｸは…｡
侍の国 ﾎﾞｸらの国が…｡
おぉ～い！
The land of samurai. The
time when our country...
Hey! Why do you have to start
all the way back there?!
ってまた
そこから回想するのかよ！
Well, this is the fateful episode
where we met.
だって ﾎﾞｸらが出会った
運命のｴﾋﾟｿｰﾄﾞですよ｡
Last year's recap episode
started from there!
つうか１年前の総集編のときも
そっから始めたろ！
We don't need that.
そこは もういらないね
次は私の登場ｼｰﾝを…｡
Let's go to my first appearance, next...
We already did that, too!
だから そこも前やったつ～の！
Reminisce about other things!
もっと いろんなところから
思い出せよ！
But when I try to look back on GinTama
and take a look at the list of titles...
だって 『銀魂』を
振り返ろうとして➡
["Nobody With Naturally Wavy
Hair Can Be That Bad"]
ｻﾌﾞﾀｲﾄﾙ一覧表とかを見ても➡
["You Only Gotta Wash Under Your
Armpits, Just the Armpits"]
何の話か さっぱりわからない
ﾀｲﾄﾙが多くて➡
It's difficult to remember anything
because a lot of the titles
["Watch Out for Conveyor Belts"]
make it impossible to tell what
the episode was about.
["You Know What Happens if You Pee on a Worm"]
思い出しづらいんですよ｡
["Do Cherries Come from Cherry Trees?"]
That's right.
["A Dog's Paws Smell Fragrant"]
そうね！ 私の初登場回の➡
The episode I first appeared in was
["The Manga Writer Becomes a Pro.
After Doing a Stock of Manuscripts"]
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは 時々 土曜日にでるから
気をつけろ｣って➡
"Watch Out! Weekly Shonen Jump Sometimes
Comes Out on Saturdays!"
["Watch Out! Weekly Shonen Jump Sometimes
Comes Out on Saturdays!"]
いったい 何ｱﾙか？
What's that supposed to mean?
あぁ
あれは親切だと思うよ｡
Oh, I think that's just being considerate.
Oh well. Then let's decide
on a theme and reminisce.
しかたねえな
じゃあ 今回は➡
ﾃｰﾏを決めて
回想していくとするか｡
たとえば 銀さんの感動したｾﾘﾌ
ﾍﾞｽﾄ10とか➡
For example: Gin-san's
top ten touching lines,
銀さんの かっこよかったﾊﾞﾄﾙｼｰﾝ
ﾍﾞｽﾄ10とか｡
or the top ten battles where
Gin-san looked cool.
Wait, why are they all
about you, Gin-san?
ちょっと！ なんで
銀さんばっかりなんですか！
Then why don't we do the top
ten episodes that received
じゃあ 視聴者から
苦情の多かった話 ﾍﾞｽﾄ10とか｡
the most complaints from the viewers?
できるか！ そんなもん！
We can't do that!
Oh yeah. Why don't we say that we're going
to reveal all of the unaired scenes
そうだ 未公開ｼｰﾝ
一挙公開とか言って➡
ﾋﾟｰ音が
ついてたところはずして➡
and air them without the bleeps?
放送してみたら
いいんじゃね？
In that case, we should remove
the scrambled parts, too.
いっそのこと
ﾓｻﾞｲｸも はずしてみたらいいね｡
We'll be immediately cancelled!
即刻 打ち切られるわ！
ﾊｧ～ だいたい 『銀魂』は➡
Anyway, it's difficult to make
a recap about GinTama
ｽﾄｰﾘｰ上の大きな流れとか➡
主人公の目標みたいのがないから
総集編が作りにくいんだよ｡
because there isn't a continuous storyline and
the main character doesn't have a goal.
たとえば 集めると願いの叶う
７つの球を探すとか➡
For example, searching for seven
balls that grant wishes,
[Note: Parody of Dragon Ball and ONE PIECE.]
海賊王に ｵﾚはなる！ とかさ｡
or trying to become the pirate king...
それ もう
ひと月前に ﾈﾀにしました｡
We did that a month ago.
あっ…｡
あっ… じゃねえよ｡
Oh...
Don't say "Oh." What are we going
to do? This is not even a recap.
どうすんだよ これ
総集編ですらないよ！
いい加減にしないと また
ﾏｼﾞでか？
偉い人に怒られますよ！
If we don't cut it out, management
will be furious again.
Really?!
ﾏｼﾞだよ 今度 誰かまた
違う人が飛ばされるよ！
I'm serious. This time, they're going
to haul another person away.
What?!
♪♪～
This is an official police bust!!
(土方)
御用改めである！
What's your problem?
なんだﾃﾒｴ ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ星の皇子
何しにきやがったﾏﾖ｡
Prince of Planet Mayo Maniac,
why are you here, mayo?
We got word there was a suspicious secret
discussion going on here, mayo...
ここで 何やら
怪しい密談をしているという➡
通報があってﾏﾖ…｡
I didn't mean to say "mayo"! What
in the world were you doing?!
って ﾏﾖじゃねえよ！
いったい ﾃﾒｴら 何してやがった！
正直に白状しねえと
しょっぴくぞ！
If you don't confess, I'll haul you in!
I won't tell you, mayo!
教えねえﾏﾖ！ だいたい
人んちに ｽﾞｶｽﾞｶあがりこんで➡
Anyway, who do you think you are, barging
into someone's house, mayo?!
ｷｻﾏこそ 何様のつもりだﾏﾖ！
ﾏﾖはやめろ!!
Stop with the "mayo"!
(沖田)
じゃあ いったい皆さんは➡
So what were you all
talking about, mayo?
何の相談をしてたんですかﾏﾖ？
Well, the GinTama anime is finally
entering its final chapter,
それがですね
ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』も➡
いよいよ
最終章 突入ということで➡
これまでを振り返りつつ
盛り上げていこうと…｡
so we thought we'd drum up some interest
by looking back on our past episodes.
Tsk. Is that all? A recap episode, huh?
ちっ なんだ
総集編の相談か｡
Don't say, "Is that all?"
なんだじゃないですよ
ｱﾆﾒ 『銀魂』が➡
We need it to help keep GinTama going
for the remaining six months.
残り 半年を走りきるためにも
重要な回なんですよ｡
いろいろ 温存しなきゃ
なんないこともあるし…｡
There are lots of things
we need to preserve.
If we don't reminisce on cool scenes
and beautify them in our memories,
かっこいいとこ回想して➡
思い出の中だけでも
美しくしとかないと➡
we won't last six months.
あと半年 もたないｱﾙ｡
ふむ かっこいいところか…｡
Hmm... Cool scenes, huh?
["Make Friends You Can Call by Their Nicknames,
Even When You're an Old Fart"]
(土方)とうとう
尻尾 出しやがった｡
He's finally exposed himself...
(土方)ふっ 山崎｡
(山崎)ﾊｯ！
Yamazaki.
Yes!
なんとしても
ﾔﾂらの拠点 抑えてこい｡
はい｡
Track down their base, at all cost.
Sir!
(土方)天人との戦で
活躍した英雄も➡
With all the Amanto in the world now,
even the hero of the Amanto
war is just another criminal.
天人さまさまの
今の世の中じゃあ➡
ただの反乱分子か｡
このご時世に
天人を追っ払うなんざ➡
It takes real guts to still be fighting
the Amanto these days.
たいした夢想家だよ｡
(土方)おい 沖田 起きろ｡
Hey, Okita, wake up.
(土方)お前 よくあの爆音のなか
寝てられるな｡
I'm surprised that you could sleep
through that explosion.
爆音って…｡
Explosion? Did you let the
terrorists attack again?
また 爆弾犯
防げなかったんですかい？
何やってんだい 土方さん
ﾏｼﾞﾒに働けよ｡
What's your problem, Hijikata-san?
You need to apply yourself.
(土方)もう１回 眠るか こら｡
You wanna sleep permanently?
(土方)天人の館が
いくら吹っ飛ぼうが➡
They can blow up all the
Amanto for all I care.
知ったこっちゃねえよ｡
I'll let those fishies swim for a bit before I'll
reel 'em in, line 'em up and cut their necks.
連中 泳がして
ｶﾞﾝ首揃ったところを➡
まとめて叩き斬ってやる｡
真選組の晴れ舞台だぜ
楽しいｹﾝｶになりそうだ｡
It'll be a proud moment for the Shinsengumi.
I'm looking forward to this fight.
Hey, that was the episode
when you first appeared!
って 自分の登場回かよ！
ｺﾞﾎﾝ じゃあ 次は
近藤さんに回想してもらおうか｡
Ahem...
Then shall we look back
on Kondo-san next?
いや 近藤さんの回想は
別にいいですよ｡
No, we don't really need to
look back on Kondo-san.
No one wants to see that.
Our ratings will drop.
誰も見たくないね
毎分が下がるｱﾙ｡
(近藤)いやいや ｵﾚも
今でこそ➡
No, no. Right now, I'm
a gorilla-like character,
ｺﾞﾘﾗっぽい感じの
ｷｬﾗになってはいるが➡
but I was cool when I first appeared.
初登場のときは そりゃあ
かっこよかったぞ｡
["There Is Butt a Fine Line Between
Persistence and Stubbornness"]
(近藤)どうせ ｵﾚなんて
ｹﾂ毛 ﾎﾞｰﾎﾞｰだしさ…｡
It's not gonna happen... Besides,
my butt hair is too thick.
女に ﾓﾃるわけないんだよ｡
There's no way a girl would
go out with me.
ﾊｧ… ﾀﾞﾒだな ｵﾚは｡
I'm no good.
That's not true. You're just very manly!
And that's attractive, isn't it?
(お妙)
そんなことないですよ｡
男らしくて
ｽﾃｷじゃありませんか｡
(近藤)じゃあ 聞くけどさ
もし お妙さんの彼氏がさ➡
Then let me ask you this...
If your boyfriend's...
ｹﾂが
毛だるまだったらどうするよ？
rear end looked like an afro with
a part down the middle, what would you do?
ｹﾂ毛ごと愛します｡
I would love him, butt afro and all.
《近藤:菩薩！
すべての不浄を包み込む➡
What a goddess!
She purifies unclean things
just like a Bodhisattva.
まるで 菩薩だ！》
Butt-butt-butt-but will you marry me!
ｹﾂ… ｹﾂ… ｹﾂ…｡
ｹﾂ婚してください!!
えっ!?
Huh?!
[Otae-san]
[Otae-san, go out with me for a hump.]
[Otae-san, marry me.]
Otae-san!! Marry me!!
お妙さん!!
ｵﾚと結婚してくれ!!
(近藤)一度や二度
ﾌﾗれたくらいじゃ ｵﾚは倒れんよ｡
I'm not the kind of man who takes
"No" for an answer twice!
My mom says women find more happiness
in being loved than in loving someone!
女はさ
愛するより 愛されるほうが➡
幸せなんだよって
母ちゃんが言ってた｡
Otae-san!
なぁ お妙さん
顔だけでも出してくんないかな！
Won't you just show your
angelic face at least?!
あっ お妙さん！
Otae-san!!
Right?! Right?!
ねっ ねっ！
Otae-san!
(近藤)お妙さん！
Kondo-san, you seem to be mistaken...
近藤さん
思い違いしているみたいだけど➡
初登場のときから！
You've been nothing but a pathetic stalker-gorilla
since you first appeared!
最低なｽﾄｰｶｰの
ｺﾞﾘﾗ野郎でしたよ！
そして 近藤さんの
敵討ちのために➡
In order to avenge Kondo-san...
副長は 再び 旦那と
対決することになるんでﾏﾖ… ﾏﾖ｡
Our Vice-Chief fought you once
again, mayo... Mayo...
["Fighting Should Be Done with Fists"]
(２人)ふんっ！
うわっ！
なに しやがんだ!? ﾃﾒｴ！
What's the big idea?!
ｺﾞﾘﾗだろうがな➡
He may be a gorilla, but to us,
he's our beloved general!
ｵﾚたちにとっちゃ
大事な 大将なんだよ！
ｺｲﾂ１本で
一緒に 真選組を作り上げてきた➡
He built the Shinsengumi up from
nothing with just one sword.
He's my brother-in-arms!
ｵﾚの戦友なんだよ！
(土方)誰にも
ｵﾚたちの真選組は 汚させねえ！
I won't let anyone shame our unit...and who
so ever crosses that line, my blade...
その道を
遮るものがあるならば…➡
ｺｲﾂで 叩き斬るのみだ～!!
...shall taste
うりゃ～!!
his blood!
Got him!
取った！
なにっ!?
What?!
《かわされた!? 斬られる！》
Parried! He got me.
Thus, Hijikata-san miserably lost, mayo.
というわけで 土方さんは
あえなく敗北したﾏﾖ｡
Stop talking like that! It's annoying!
その口調 やめろ！
むかつくんだけど～！
やっぱ かっこいいとこは
銀ちゃんが もっていくｱﾙ～！
Gin-chan really does steal
the cool scenes.
But this isn't the only grudge between the
Shinsengumi and the Odd Jobs, mayo.
だが… 真選組と万事屋の因縁は
これだけじゃねえんでﾏﾖ｡
えっ？ 何かありましたっけ？
Huh? Did something happen?
Oh! That episode where Otae-san
and I were united!
あっ!! お妙さんとｵﾚが結ばれた
あの ｴﾋﾟｿｰﾄﾞ!!
ねえよ！ そんな ｴﾋﾟｿｰﾄﾞ｡
There is no such episode.
はんっ！ あったじゃねえか｡
There was an episode where the
Odd Jobs had a full-scale battle!
万事屋と真選組が 全面対決した
あの ｴﾋﾟｿｰﾄﾞが!!
["Even if You Aren't Drunk, Pretend You
Are and Steal Your Boss's Toupee"]
Here you go, a bento box lunch.
は～い！ お弁当ですよ～！
Sorry for barging in on a family outing.
わりいな おい…｡
兄弟 水入らずのとこ➡
ｼﾞｬﾏしちゃって…｡
(お妙)いいのよ～！
That's all right.
２人で お花見なんてしても
寂しいもの…｡
It wouldn't be any fun viewing the cherry
blossoms with just the two of us.
Right, Shin-chan?
(お妙)ねっ！ 新ちゃん！
お父上が健在の頃は➡
When our father was still alive,
よく ３人…
桜の下ではじけたものだわ｡
the three of us used to party like
crazy under the cherry trees.
さっ お食べになって｡
Now, eat up.
Well then, I'll dig in.
じゃ 遠慮なく…｡
(２人)あっ…｡
なんですか？ これは…｡ ｱｰﾄ？
What the heck is this-a sculpture?
私 ﾀﾏｺﾞ焼きしか作れないの…｡
I can only make omelets.
ﾀﾏｺﾞ焼きじゃねえだろう？
これは焼けたﾀﾏｺﾞだよ？
This isn't an omelet. This is a burnt egg.
ﾀﾏｺﾞが焼けていれば
それが どんな状態だろうと➡
No matter what state it's in, as long
as the egg is cooked, it's an omelet.
ﾀﾏｺﾞ焼きよ｡
違うよ｡
No, it's not. This isn't an omelet.
It's an innocent, abused egg.
これは ﾀﾏｺﾞ焼きじゃなくて
かわいそうな ﾀﾏｺﾞだよ｡
いいから 男は 黙って食えや～!!
You're a man, so shut up and just eat it!!
If I don't eat this, I'll die.
If I eat this, I'll die.
これを食べないと 死ぬんだ｡
暗示かけてまで 食わんでいいわ!!
You don't need to convince
yourself to eat it!!
やめときなって…｡
ﾎﾞｸのように 目が悪くなるよ｡
Don't eat it. Your eyes
will go bad like mine.
ｶﾞﾊﾊﾊ～!! まったく
しようがないﾔﾂらだな～！
You guys really are pitiful.
どれ！ ｵﾚが食べてやるから➡
C'mon, give it to me... I'll eat it.
このﾀｯﾊﾟｰに入れておきなさい！
Just scoop some into this
Tupperware container.
なに ﾚｷﾞｭﾗｰみたいな顔して
座ってんだ ｺﾞﾘﾗ～!!
Why are you sitting here as if you're
a regular customer, you gorilla!
どっからわいて出た～!?
What rock did you crawl out from under?!
Whoa. Geez, is that stalker still after her?
おいおい…
まだ ｽﾄｰｶｰ被害に遭ってたのか？
町奉行に
相談したほうがいいって…｡
Maybe you should talk
to the town magistrate.
いや…
あの人が 警察らしいんすよ｡
No, apparently he's a police officer.
It's the end of the world...
世も末だな…｡
(土方)悪かったな…｡
Sorry about that...
Uh-oh. What do all you
ugly guys want with us?
おうおう！ ﾑｻい連中が
ぞろぞろと 何の用ですか？
Are you hunting for mushrooms?
ｷﾉｺ狩りですか？
そこをどけ｡
Move out of our spot.
そこは 毎年 真選組が
花見をする際に使う特別席だ｡
That's a special spot the Shinsengumi
uses for cherry blossom
viewing every year.
What kind of excuse is that?
どういう言いがかりだ？
こんなもん
どことでも同じだろうが｡
Every spot is the same. What are
you, the 24-hour police thugs?!
ﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗ警察24時か？ ﾃﾒｴら！
It's not the same! The cherry blossoms
look extra special from there!
同じじゃねえ｡ そこから
見える桜は 特別なんだよ｡
Isn't that right, guys?
なぁ みんな～！
Well, I don't really care so long
as I can get smashed.
(隊士)いや～ 別に ｵﾚたちは➡
酒 呑めりゃ
どこでもいいっすわ～！
I don't mind if we sit on
the asphalt or wherever.
(隊士)ｱｽﾌｧﾙﾄの上だろうと
どこだろうと かまいませんぜ｡
Even sitting on asphalt, I can get in the
flower-watching mood if I have a drink.
酒のためなら ｱｽﾌｧﾙﾄに咲く
花のようになれますぜ｡
…うるせえ!! ほんとは ｵﾚも
どこでもいいんだが➡
Shut up!! I actually couldn't
care less either.
ｺｲﾂのために場所 変更しなきゃ
ならねえのが気に食わねえ!!
But I don't like the fact that we have
to move because of this jerk!
(土方)だいたい 山崎
場所取りに行かせたはずだろ!?
Anyway, we sent Yamazaki
to save our spot, didn't we?
(土方)どこ 行った!? ｱｲﾂは…！
Where did he go?
He's playing badminton.
(沖田)ﾐﾝﾄﾝ やってますぜ｡ ﾐﾝﾄﾝ｡
Yamazaki!!
(土方)山崎～!!
うわぁぁぁ～っ!!
(土方)山崎…!!
(山崎)ﾗｹｯﾄが…！ ﾗｹｯﾄが…!!
まぁ…
とにかく そういうことなんだ｡
Well, anyway, that's the case.
こちらも
毎年恒例の 行事なんでね➡
We use this spot every
year, so just move.
おいそれと 変更できん！
お妙さんだけ残して
去ってもらおうか～！
We want everyone besides
Otae-san to leave.
No, Otae-san leaves with you.
いや…
お妙さんごと 去ってもらおうか｡
いや… お妙さんは ﾀﾞﾒだってば！
No, Otae-san stays.
Who the hell do you schmucks think
you are, ordering us around?
な～に 勝手 抜かしてんだ｡
幕臣だか なんだか知らねえが➡
ｵﾚたちを どかしてえなら
ﾌﾞﾙﾄﾞｰｻﾞｰでも 持ってこいよ！
If you want to do something about
us, then bring a bulldozer.
Bring a dozen cartons of Bäagen-Dash.
ﾊﾞｰｹﾞﾝﾀﾞｯｼｭ １ﾀﾞｰｽ 持ってこいよ！
Bring some fried chicken.
ﾌﾗｲﾄﾞﾁｷﾝの皮 持ってこいよ！
(定春のうなり声)
案外 お前ら 簡単に動くな…｡
You move pretty easily, don't you?
Oh that's rich...talking back to
the bakufu government, eh?
おもしれえ…｡ 幕府に 逆らうか？
今年は 桜じゃなくて
血の舞う花見に なりそうだな…｡
It looks like we'll be watching blood
swirl, instead of cherry blossoms.
ﾃﾒｴとは
毎回 こうなる運命のようだ｡
It looks like we're destined
to do this every year.
この間の借りは
返させてもらうぜ！
I'm going to pay you back
for what you did last time!
(沖田)待ちなせえ！
Hold it!
We can't have you guys sword
fighting out in the open
(沖田)ｶﾀｷﾞの皆さんが
まったりしてる場で➡
ﾁｬﾝﾊﾞﾗとは いただけねえや｡
with innocent civilians nearby.
ここは ひとつ
花見らしく 決着 つけましょうや｡
Let's settle this in a Cherry
Blossom spirit.
第１回！ 陣地争奪
たたいて かぶって ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ大会!!
The First Annual... Mallet and Helmet-style
rock paper scissors contest!!
(銀時たち)花見 関係ねえじゃん!!
That has nothing to do with
cherry blossom viewing!!
(沖田)説明しよう｡ たたいて
かぶって ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ！ とは➡
[Mallet and Helmet-style
Rock Paper Scissors]
[You need: a helmet, a toy hammer]
Let me explain. In Mallet and
Helmet rock paper scissors...
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝをし
勝ったほうが 殴りかかり➡
You play one round of
rock paper scissors...
The winner gets to hit the loser.
ﾍﾙﾒｯﾄで防がれたら ｾｰﾌ｡
The loser is safe if he blocks
it with his helmet,
ﾋｯﾄすれば 勝ち｡
but the winner wins the
game if he gets a hit in.
Anyway, it's something like that.
It's a wild and aggressive game.
とまぁ こんな感じの
ﾜｲﾙﾄﾞ＆ｱｸﾞﾚｯｼﾌﾞな ｹﾞｰﾑなのだ｡
(喚声)
Go, Chief!
(隊士たち)いけ～ 局長!!
Die, Vice-Chief!
(沖田)死ね 副長！
(土方)誰だ!?
Who just told me to die?!
Seppuku for you, damn it!
(土方)今 ｢死ね｣っつったの！
切腹だ ｺﾗ～!!
(山崎)え～ 勝負は 両陣営 代表➡
Umm... This challenge
will be decided by...
three representatives from each side.
３人による勝負で 決まります｡
(山崎)審判も 公平を期して➡
To be fair, Shinpachi-kun and I, Yamazaki,
will be the judges.
両陣営から
新八君と ｵﾚ… 山崎が➡
つとめさせていただきます｡
The winner wins the right to view cherry
blossoms from here and gets Otae-san.
勝ったほうは
ここで 花見をする権利｡
ﾌﾟﾗｽ お妙さんを 得るわけです｡
What kind of rules are those?!
What are you, kidnappers?!
なに その 勝手なﾙｰﾙ!!
ｱﾝﾀら 山賊!?
それじゃあ ﾎﾞｸら
勝っても負けても➡
We don't gain anything
by winning or losing.
ﾌﾟﾗﾏｲ ｾﾞﾛでしょうが!!
Then we'll give you a Shinsengumi sausage.
じゃあ ｷﾐらには
ﾌﾟﾗｽ 真選組ｿｰｾｰｼﾞだ！
屯所の冷蔵庫に 入ってた！
It was in the headquarters' refrigerator.
ようするに ただの
ｿｰｾｰｼﾞじゃねえかっ!! いるかっ!!
In other words, it's just an ordinary
sausage! We don't need that!!
ｿｰｾｰｼﾞだってよ
気張ってこうぜ！
A sausage, he says. Let's go for it.
おう！
ﾊﾞｶかっ!! お前ら ﾊﾞｶかっ!!
All right.
Idiots!! You guys are total idiots!!
[Round One:
Chief Kondo vs Otae-san]
Let's begin the first round!
Chief Kondo versus Otae!
姉上 ﾑﾘしないでください｡
ﾎﾞｸ 代わりますよ｡
Sis, don't push yourself.
I'll take your place.
(お妙)いいえ…
私が行かないと 意味がないの｡
No, there's no honor in this
unless I do it myself.
あの人 どんなにつぶしても
立ち上がってくるの｡
That man keeps popping up no matter
how many times I crush him.
私 もう疲れちゃった｡
I'm sick of it...
すべて 終わらせてくるね｡
I'm going to end to it right here and now.
《やばい… あの目は…》
This is bad. That look in her eyes...
それでは…
たたいて かぶって…｡
Well then...
Get ready to play...
(山崎/近藤/お妙)ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ！
Rock, paper...
Scissors!!
お～っと ｾｰﾌ!!
Whew, I'm safe!!
ｾｰﾌじゃない!! 逃げろ 近藤さん!!
You're not safe! Run away, Kondo-san!
Huh?
天魔外道皆仏性四魔三障成道
来魔界仏界同如理一相平等…！
Spirits of heaven and hell,
give me strength!
Huh? Huh?
Use me as an instrument
of divine judgment!!
ちょっと お妙さん… これ！
もう ﾍﾙﾒｯﾄ かぶってるから！
Hey, Otae-san, I already
have the helmet on...
てぇええいっ!!
That's not in...the rules.
[That's not in...the rules]
Chief!
(みんな)局長～!!
What the hell did you
do, you evil wench?!
ﾃﾒｴ 何しやがんだ！ ｸｿ女！
ああ～ん？ やんのか ｺﾗ～！
Oh... So you want to fight, too?
(みんな)すいませんでした～！
We're very sorry.
新八君… ｷﾐも大変だね｡
Shinpachi-kun, you have
it rough, don't you?
もう慣れましたよ｡
I'm used to it.
(山崎)ええと
局長が戦闘不能になったので➡
Umm... The Chief is unable to continue,
so the first round is a draw.
一戦目は
無効試合とさせていただきます｡
二戦目の人は
最低限のﾙｰﾙを守って…｡
For the second round,
both contestants please try to
at least follow the rules...
(どよめき)
Whoa!
(隊士)もう始まってんぞ！
(隊士)速え！ ものすげえ速え！
They've already started!
They're fast!! They're super fast!!
They're so fast it looks like they both
have a hammer and a helmet.
(隊士)あまりの速さに ２人とも
ﾒｯﾄと ﾊﾝﾏｰを➡
持ったままのように見えるぞ!!
(みんな)おおお～！
Oh? She's evenly matched
against Sogo?
(土方)ほぅ…
総吾と互角にやりあうとは➡
何者だ？ あの娘｡
ﾔﾂは 頭は空だが➡
Who is that girl?
Sogo's got no brains,
腕は 真選組でも
最強をうたわれる男だぜ｡
but he's got the strongest sword
arm in the Shinsengumi.
互角だぁ？ ｳﾁの神楽に
人が勝てると思ってんの？
Evenly matched?
You think a human can
stand up to Kagura?
ﾔﾂはなぁ 絶滅寸前の戦闘種族
夜兎なんだぜ｡ すごいんだぜ｡
She's a member of the nearly
extinct race of warriors,
the Yato clan. She's amazing.
なんだと～？ ｳﾁの総吾はな～！
ｳﾁの神楽だってな～！
What? Well, our Sogo...
Well, our Kagura...
おい～ ﾀﾞｻｲからやめて～！
Hey, knock it off!
ｵﾚの父ちゃんﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄ って言ってる
子供なみに ﾀﾞｻｲよ～！
You sound ridiculous-like little kids
bragging "my daddy is a pilot"!!
っていうか ｱﾝﾀら 何飲んでんの!?
Never mind that. Did you guys
start drinking already?!
あん？
勝負は もう始まってんだよ｡
Huh? Our round started already.
Okay, next up tequila.
よし 次は ﾃｷｰﾗ！
上等だ！
Bring it on.
あ～ぁ… 勝手に
飲み比べ始めちゃってるよ｡
Man, they're in their own world
with that drinking contest.
(隊士たち)おお～！
Wow. The battle on this side
has become ever fiercer.
(山崎)ああ～ こうしてるうちに
こっちは もっと苛烈に…！
あれ？ ちょっと待って！
Huh? Wait a minute...
Both of them are clearly
wearing a helmet.
(隊士)２人とも 明らかに
ﾒｯﾄつけたまんまじゃねえか！
ﾊﾝﾏｰないし！
なんか ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝもしてねえぞ！
And they don't have hammers.
They're not even playing
rock paper scissors.
ただの 殴り合いじゃないか！
They're just beating the
crap out of each other!!
だから ﾙｰﾙ守れって
言ってんだろうがっ!!
I told you to follow the rules!!
これも 収拾不可能だな～｡
This is so out of control.
しようがない… 最後の対決で
決めるしかない｡ 銀さん…｡
Oh well. We have to decide
this with the final showdown.
Gin-sa...
(銀時/土方)おぇぇぇ～｡
おいい～！ 何やってんだ～!!
このままじゃ 勝負つかねえよ!!
Hey! What are you doing?
You two can't fight like this!
心配すんじゃねえや｡
ｵﾚは まだやれる！
Don't worry. I can still do
this. Let's settle this...
白黒 はっきり
つけようじゃねえか｡
上等だ ｺﾗ…｡
Bring it on, damn it!
It would be boring to settle
things normally.
このまま
普通にやってもつまらねえ｡
ここは どうだ？ 真剣で➡
Why don't we play some
"Cut and Parry-style
｢斬って かわして ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ｣
にしねえか？
rock-paper scissors" using real swords?
上等だ ｺﾗ！
Bring it on, damn it!
お前 さっきから
｢上等だ｣しか言ってねえぞ｡
"Bring it on" is all you've been saying.
ｵﾚが言うのもなんだけど
大丈夫か？
I feel weird asking you this,
but are you all right?
上等だ ｺﾗ～!!
Bring it on, damn it!!
山崎！ ｺｲﾂに刀を！
Yamazaki, give him a sword!!
Huh?
え!? あっ はいはい！
ええ!?
Sure! Sure!
刀なんか渡しちゃ
ﾀﾞﾒじゃないですか!!
え… だって｡
You shouldn't have given him a sword.
Huh?! But...
いくぜ！
上等だ ｺﾗ～！
Let's do this!
Bring it on, damn it!
(２人)せぇの！
Ready?
(２人)斬って かわして ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ!!
Cut and parry-style rock paper...
Scissors!!
とった～っ!!
I win!!
心配するな… みねうちだ｡
Don't worry. I used the back of my sword.
まぁ これに懲りたら もう
ｵﾚに絡むのは やめるこったな｡
Well, I hope you've learned your
lesson-don't mess with me.
ﾃﾒｴ！ さっきから
ｸﾞｰしか出してねえじゃねえか！
Hey you! You throw "rock" every time!
なめてんのか ｵﾒｴ！
どうした？ ｸﾞｰの音も出ないか？
Are you trying to make a fool of me?!
What's wrong? You aren't
saying anything.
だから なめてんのかって
言ってんだろ ｵﾒｴ!!
Are you trying to make
a fool of me, huh?!
お互い
妙な上司がいて大変ですね｡
We both have pretty strange bosses.
まったく｡
Yeah...
＜父上… やっぱり 花見は
大勢でやるもんですね｡
Father, cherry blossoms are really best
when viewed with a large group.
父上が亡くなって以来です｡
こんなに楽しい お花見は…＞
This is the most fun I've had
viewing cherry blossoms
since you passed away.
Come on, Shin-chan...
さぁ 新ちゃん｡
あ… それは その…｡
Oh, that's umm...
♪♪～
あれ？ ここどこ？
Huh? Where am I?
…ということで なんとか
30分 埋まりましたね！
And so, we managed to fill
up thirty minutes of time.
まっ 本当に
ただの総集編だったがな｡
Well, it really was just a recap episode.
ﾌﾟﾛﾃﾞｭｰｻｰは また始末書かな？
Will the producer have to
write another apology?
(神楽)大丈夫！
…とかでも よくやってる➡
It's all right. This happens
a lot with [bleep] as well.
[Note: Bleep covers Code Geass.]
ｻﾝﾗｲｽﾞの困ったときの
お得意のﾊﾟﾀｰﾝね！
It's Sunrise's usual problematic pattern.
Well, anyway, we'll finally be entering
the final chapter next week!
あっ まぁ そんなこんなで
いよいよ来週から 最終章 突入！
We still have half a year, so let's not
exert ourselves and drag it on.
半年もあるんで
気張らずに ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗやろうぜ｡
(神楽)ひょっとして また
４年目延長とか➡
We might extend into our fourth year!
あるかもしれないｱﾙよ｡
(銀時/新八)ない ない！
That won't happen.
Oh, we forgot the cast credits.
[So anyway, we'd like to drag
on until the final episode.]
[Also, we won't be doing these crappy
recaps or whatever anymore.]
あ… ｷｬｽﾄ ｸﾚｼﾞｯﾄし忘れてた｡